→ https://csmerrell.com ← Sample App showcase

A 5-year, mid-senior-level web developer versed in a breadth of libraries and skills. Emphasis in front end engineering and UI/UX design. Self-learner, heavily invested in ownership of the product. Past roles include Senior Development; Task Management & Delegation; UI/UX Design & Architecture.

HIGHLIGHTS

Led teams of 2-5 developers.

Rapid-prototyped a startup software suite in 4 months.

Overhauled, rewrote, refactored, and iterated on 20+ legacy code bases.

Launched 5+ applications start to finish. Contributed to & launched dozens more.

Conceptualized, pitched, designed, and maintained intuitive user experience design in all products.

SKILLS

HTML / CSS / Javascript Vue / React / Angular Ajax, REST api Sass JS Libraries (JQuery, Lodash) NPM, Gulp, Build Tools Agile & Scrum Git UI / UX & Responsive Design ASP.Net (MVC, Core) Data Structures, Data Schema Typescript, Prototypes, Closures Node.js / Express.js C#, Java, Object Oriented Design Markdown Documentation SQL. Relational Databases CICD

WORK EXPERIENCE

Naval Air Weapons Station, China Lake, CA Front End Lead Developer; UI / UX Architect & Engineer Feb 2017 - Present

- Overhauled 2 major systems over 3.5 years. Led major segments of 1 of these systems.
- Stack: JS/Vue; Sass/CSS; HTML; Handlebars; ASP.Net (MVC, Core); MSSQL; Gulp; Git.
- JS, VueJS, Markdown:
 - Built, tested, and documented 4 highly-portable Vue components for 10+ years of expected use.
 - Reviewed, wrote, and tested data-bound forms and limited-scope components across 3 major applications over 3.5 years of development.
- Light/Dark mode dual-theming (CSS3):
 - Implemented a large-scale user controllable dual-theme into the team's core application with zero significant theme-related development or maintenance issues in over a year of use.
 - Live implementation available at demo web app: https://csmerrell.com.
- ASP.Net (MVC, Core), C#, SQL / MSSQL:

- Defined api (preconditions, parameter specifications, postconditions, return specifications) for hundreds of versioned REST endpoints.
- Wrote MSSQL stored procedures and SQL scripts for an 8-month full stack project.
- Git SCM, Version Control, Agile & Scrum:
 - o Reviewed 2-8 merges for teammates per sprint. Reported in daily standups for 3 years.
 - Assigned and delegated front end tasks for 2-week sprint cycles.
- Bonus: Interned (3-5 months) with 4 teams from varied technical backgrounds. Noteworthy experience:.
 - Data Science HR recruitment, retention, attrition modeling with ensemble machine learning algorithms (3+ ML models in concert).
 - Networked and Facilitated 5+ meetings with diverse groups of professionals to learn hiring pains and experiment with machine learning models to solve key concerns.

Chromatic.ai (Failed Startup), Provo, UT Sole Front End Developer; UI / UX Architect & Engineer

May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Rapid-prototyped a minimum viable cloud logging SPA software suite in 4 months. Highlighted features included:.
 - Primary log viewer & querying interface with bespoke components for filtering and configuration housed inside a dockable, collapsible, multi-tab panel (10+ user filter components. 30+ additional basic filters).
 - Log send/retrieve protocol with configuration and documentation guides for 3 common industry logging environments.
- Stack: Reactjs; Django; Elastic Search; Docker & Kubernetes; Git/Travis-Cl; Karma Testing.

Brigham Young University, Provo, UT Full Stack Developer; New Employee Trainer

Oct 2014 - Nov 2016

- Built & finished 3 new content management & scheduling systems. Maintained others.
- Trained five 2nd-year CS students into professional full stack development.
- Collected feedback from interviews and product demos with stakeholders (university professors).
- Stack: Angular (1.0); Sass; ASP.Net (MVC, Web Forms); MSSQL.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science - Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah

Graduation - Dec 2016

ADDITIONAL CONTACT

Ridgecrest, California 93555 - (801) 717-5897